Gareth Davies

8 Venice Court, Wake Green Park, Moseley, Birmingham B13 9YL

info@garethdavies.me

07846861028

Summary

I am a highly skilled creative professional with over 8 years experience working with web sites and web applications. I am adaptable, self-motivated and organised in my working approach. I am currently working as a Senior Designer at the New Technology Institute in Birmingham, which demands a wealth of web experience; including technical, creative and client facing skills. I have a wide skill-set that makes me an asset to have on any web development team, working on projects from initial briefs through to final implementation.

Employment

Senior Designer

NTI Birmingham 2008 - Present In this role I have been involved in numerous web projects which have required me to providing cost and time estimations, deal with client requests and meetings, complete usability and accessibility testing, collaborate with other designers and developers and assigning tasks to them while monitoring project development. During this period I have developed my knowledge of ASP.NET, HTML5, CSS3 and JQuery and utilised these new skills during recent projects.

Web Designer

Media Content Lab 2003 - 2008 I joined Media Content Lab as a Web Designer in 2003. During this period I had a very diverse role working across a wide range of projects from graphic design, branding, and web design. I designed and built numerous websites using HTML, CSS, ASP and Flash technologies while refining my knowledge of accessibility and usability issues. Dealing with client meetings and inquiries gave me valuable experience in expressing creative ideas and processes.

Freelance

Web Designer 2001 - 2003 I worked on a variety of web projects in a freelance capacity after graduating from university. During this time I also worked on a voluntary basis for Birmingham based website designers CleverCherry.com to gain industry experience. I believe the first-hand experience of working in a successful design studio was integral in me receiving an offer of full time employment from Media Content Lab.

Education

1998 - 2001

BA(Hons) Design Studies University of Salford

1996 - 1998

A-Level - Design Studies, Physics & Geography

Cadbury College, Birmingham

Skills

Software

Visual Studio, Dreamweaver, Fireworks, Photoshop, SQL Server Management Studio

Languages

HTML, CSS, ASP.NET C#, JavaScript, JQuery, XML, ASP, SQL, PHP

Tools & Databases

SQL Server, IIS, Microsoft Access, Apache, MySQL